In this lesson, we want to learn that how we can install pie charts and also how you can create your
first line chart using pie cutie.
So first of all, what is line chart?
Now line charts are typically presented as a series of pints, or we can say markers that are connected
by lines and a line chart.
The points are connected by straight lines to show the changes of the variables over period of time.
Now let's create a practical example.
Now, before creating of our example for the line chart, we need to install pie charts because by default
we don't have charts and pie cut.
And for that we need to install a pie charts library so you can just use Pip install and after that
the library name.
Let me just install this.
And here in the terminal we can just paste this and after that hit enter.
Now, if you're using Pyqt5, then you need to install this library.
You cannot use this library for pyqt5 and for Pyqt5.
You can just use this library.
Now our pie charts has been installed.
So let's create another directory in here and I'm going to just call it part seven.
And in here we are going to create a new Python file.
And let me just call it line chart.
So first, let's create our first window using pie cut.
And so first we need some imports, dot cut widgets.
We are going to import application and also main window.
After that we are going to import dot cut.
We are going to import queue icon because we want to add an icon for our window.
Also, we need to copy the icon folder from here from part one and we can add that in the part seven.
And in here we have just a simple python dot PNG.
And after this we need to import our charts library.
So from Python six dot cut up charts we are going to import Q chart and also Q chart view.
Now, when you're going to create charts, these two are important.
Now we will have a Q chart and after that we will have a chart view.
We can add the Q chart to the chart view, and after that you can add the type of the chart that what
type you want to create.
For example, we are going to use Q line series.
Now, Q line series means that we want to create a line chart and also we are going to import says.
So now let's create our class window.
And this class extends from main window.
I'm not going to describe all of them because I've already described that you can create your first
window using pie cut and we can just create this in here.
And let me just add my init and also super function in here.
So dot.
Uh, in it.
And after this, let's set the geometry of the window.
It means the X and Y position and also the width and height of the window.
Also, we need to set the window title.
So set window title.
And I can just say, for example, our line chart and we can set the icon.
So set window icon and it expects icon.
We have already imported icon in here and here you can give the name of the icon.
So that is in the images folder we have Python dot PNG.
Now let's create the instance of the application class.
So in here I can just say app application.
I can pass this dot argument V or argv.
After that, we can create the object of our window class and now we need to show the window and at
the end we need to execute our app so we can just say sess dot exit, app dot execute.
So now if I run this, you will see that I have just a simple window.
Now let's just create our line chart or line series.
So the first thing is that in here I'm going to just create a method.
So I'm going to just call it diff line chart.
And after that we need to create our line series.
So line series.
And now we need to append some data or we can say some points to this series or line series.
Now in here we need to import another class.
So from Picked6 dot core, we are going to import cube point F, so cue point f.
And now up in here, we can just say dot append and we can add a list in here, a list of Q point F,
So we can just give some points in here like this and Q point F, we can add another one like this.
Q point F, uh, three and 268 And also we can just use some more Q point F, So it's a floating point
four and.
Like this.
Let's create another one.
And this is five.
120.
And the last one.
Let's give another one.
And this is the last one.
We can just give it 210 like this.
So after adding our pints to the line series.
Now we need to create a chart.
The object of the chart.
As I've already said that in every for example, every chart that we want to create first, we need
to create the instance of the chart, and after that we need to create the chart view.
We can add the charts and the chart view.
Now let's say chart chart and now we can add our series in the chart.
So add series and we can just add it in here.
And after doing this, we now we need to create our chart view.
And now I can just say chart.
Chart.
View.
Chart View.
Let's add the chart and the chart view.
And after that we can set the central widget to the chart view.
Now let's call our line chart.
So self dot, line chart.
And now if I run this.
So you can see that we have a line chart in here.
Now you can add some more options in here.
For example, we can create a default axis in here.
So we can just say create default axis and also we can set a title.
So set title, we can just say line chart example.
Now you can see that we have some default axis.
And also we have our line chart in here.
Line chart title.
Also, you can add animation.
So you can just say chart dot set animation options.
There are different animations that you can use.
So if we say animation options dot, you can see we have all animations, we have series animations,
for example, if I choose all animations.
And if I run this, you can see that we have a nice animation here.
Let me just run it again.
So this is the animation that we have.
And if I say, for example, series animations.
So you can see that we have another type of animations in here.
Also, you can set a theme for the chart.
So I can just say chart dot, set theme, and then here we can use chart.
Also, there are different chart theme that you can use.
For example, we can use a chart theme dark.
And if I run this so you can see we have a dark, dark theme for this.
So like this you can create a line chart and peaked.