In this lesson, we want to learn that how you can create pie chart or pie series and picked.
So now let's create a practical example.
Let me create a new python file in here and I'm going to just call it pie chart dot pie.
So first of all, we are going to just add our window code in here and we can change this to main window.
And let me change this to main window and we can add a window title.
So let me just say pie chart.
Now after creating of our main window.
Now let's add some imports from Pict six dot acuity charts.
We are going to import a chart Q chart view and also cube pie series like this.
After this, let's create our method in here and I'm going to just call it diff pie.
And in here first we need to create our pie series.
So pie series.
And after that we can add some, we can append some data.
So for example, we can just start Python and we can add the value in here series, dot append and cplusplus
and we can add a value in here series dot append, we can add a Java and after that we can add a value
and also dot append.
We can add C-sharp and let's add a volume here.
So after adding this, let's create our chart in here.
So I can just say chart chart and now we can add our series to the chart.
So chart dot Add series and we want to add our series in here after this.
We need to create chart view in here so I can just say chart view and we can add our chart in the chart
view.
And at the end we need to just set the central widget.
So self dot set central widget to the chart view.
Let's call our this solve dot pie chart in here.
And now if I run this, you can see that Now I have a pie chart in here.
Also, you can add animation or set animation for your pie chart.
So for example, up in here we can say chart dot, set animation options.
Chart dot animation options dot all animations.
And also we can set the title.
So dot set title.
Or we can just say pie chart.
Pie chart.
Example.
So now if I run this, you can see that we have a simple animation.
And also, let me just run it again.
So we have animation and also we have title in here.
Also you can add a theme for the chart.
So for example, in here we can just say chart, dot, set.
The team.
And also now we can add the type.
There are different types that you can use.
Chart team dot, for example, chart, uh, Team Blue.
So you can see that we have, uh, it's changed.
And also you can add, uh, legend, uh, for right now, if you see in here, uh, we have the legend
in this section.
Now, if you want to make it disable, you can just use chart dot legend.
Uh, dot set visible, and we can just make it to false.
So if I run this, you can see that we don't have the legend in here.
Now, let me just comment this, uh, also, you can change the position of the legend.
So right now it's on the top.
You can just make that to the bottom.
So for example, we can use dot legend, dot set alignment.
And first we need to import.
So from core, we are going to import.
And in here we can use dot alignment, flag dot line bottom.
So if I run this and now you can see that this legend is in the bottom.
Uh.
Also, you can add a slice for the chart, for the pie chart for that in here, let me just say add
a slice.
So misspelling.
Add a slice.
Now we can say my slice and we can use series dot slices and I want to add the slice for index two so
you can see zero index one index and this is index two.
I want to add a slice for the Java and we can just say my slice dot set, explode it and make this to
true.
And also we can just say my slide dot set label visible and we can make it to true.
So now if I run this, you can see that now we have the Java and it's exploded and we have the slice
of Java in here.