In this lesson, we want to create a bar chart or bar series.
Let me create a new python file in here and I'm going to just call it bar chart.
And so this is my simple window code and let me change the title to bar chart.
So now first we need to add our imports dot charts.
We are going to import chart.
Our chart view and also Cube bar series.
And also we need to import cube bar set.
Or we need to add a percent bar series.
So percent bar series.
Now let's create our add Create bar app.
So first we need to create our setting here and we can just say Q bar set.
And let me just add some names in here.
Set one.
AQ bar set
and let me just copy and paste.
This.
So this is, uh.
Let me just add a name in here, and we can change this to bar set to.
And also we can create another one.
So this is the last one.
And I can add a name and we can change this to bar set three.
So after creating of our sets.
Now let's add some data to these bar sets.
Now let me paste the data.
So these are some data that I have added in the bar sets some value.
And after adding this, now let's create our series in here so we can just say Series Cube person,
City Bar series, and now we can append the sets in here.
So set.
Zero and dot append.
Set one.
Dot append.
Set two and dot append.
And this is set three.
So after creating this, let's create our chart in here.
So chart.
Chart.
And we can add the series in the chart.
And after that we can create our chart view.
In here chart view.
And let's add the chart and the chart view.
And after that we can just say self dot set central widget to the chart view.
Now let's run this and the bar chart.
So we are not seeing any chart because we need to call this.
So self dot create bar.
Now you can see that we are seeing our bar charts in here.
You can add some, for example, animations or title to the chart as we have already done.
And we can just say chart dot, set animation options, chart dot animation options dot for example,
all animations, we can add titles.
So chart dot, set title and we can say bar chart.
Example.
Now, also you can add a theme for the chart.
So you can just say chart dot set, and we can just say chart dot chart, theme dot.
And there different we are going to use, for example, dark.
And now if I run this so you can see that this is our chart.
We have a theme and also we have animation for that.