We have already studied how we can create a person bar series and picked.
Now, in this lesson we want to create a stacked bar series and we are going to create a temperature
bar chart.
Now let's create our example.
So I've already copied my window code and let me change the title to a stacked bar series.
And now I need my imports from picked6 dot charts.
I'm going to import a cue bar set.
Q.
Stacked Bar series.
We need a Q value axis.
Q Chart.
Q chart view.
And also Q Bar category access.
Now let me create my, uh, bar set in here so I can just say low Q bar set, and let me just say mean.
And also I can just give high and we can say Q bar set and let's add Max in here.
Now we need to append some data to the these bar sets to the low and high.
So let me just paste the data.
And these are the data that I'm going to add.
So low dot append.
These are the set of the data and the list of the data.
And after that for the high also I'm going to append some value in here.
After that, we need to create our stacked bar series.
So series Q stacked bar series.
And now we can append our High and low and the Stacked Bar series.
So series dot append.
And we can add our low and dot paint.
We can add the high in here.
Now, after this, let's create our chart in here and also we can add the series to the chart.
Also, we can set the title so I can just say temperature
record and for example, sell CEUs like this.
And after this, now we need to create our category.
So these are some categories of the month that I have pasted in here.
And let's create our, uh, category axis so I can just say axis X.
Uh, Q bar category.
And now we can append.
So dot append, and we can add the categories in here.
And also we can just set the title, not title phone, but it should be, uh.
Subtitle, title, text, and we can just say Matt and.
So now after setting the title text, now we can add that to the chart.
So chart dot add axis and we can just add axis X and also we need to import from picked6 dot cuticle.
We are going to import acuity.
We need to give the alignment for this axis so we can just say cutie dot alignment, flag dot align
bottom and after this we can create the chart view in here and we can just say chart view and let's
add that in the chart to the chart view.
And also we can just say self dot set central widget to the chart view.
So before this, let's create our so we have created our axis X.
Also we need to create axis Y so that will be a value for the value axis.
So in here we can just say axis y and Q value axis and let's add a dot set range -52 and also 52.
Now let's set title.
Title Text to temperature.
And so we can add the sign of the degree in here.
So this is the sign of degree.
And after that we can add that to the chart.
So dot add axis, axis y dot alignment, flag dot align left.
So we want to add this in the left of the chart and now we can just say series dot attach.
Access.
So the first one is X, and also we can attach the Y.
So now let's run this.
So we should run this from here.
Okay.
Now you can see that we have our temperature record, and this is our temperature data.
And we have a stacked bar chart in here also.
These are the months.