Let's create our line chart and also bar chart together.
I can create a new python file.
And let me just say line bar chart.
And this is our simple code for creating out the window line line chart and.
Bar chart.
So now let's add our imports in here, so from kutty charts, we are going to import Kubra Buckyball
set.
We need a CubeSat series.
We need to chart view and also queue chart and also queue line cities.
So and here first, we need to create our basket.
So let me just start at zero Q Marcet and we can just act.
Some names in here, and let me just copy this.
For example, Bob.
And also, we can create another one, and this should be told.
And let me just add another one, and this should be Mary and also Sam.
Now, let's change this to Borsa to three and also four.
So now after creating of the bar set to now, we need to add some detail where upends some data to this
to this these baskets that we have created.
Now, let me paste my data in here so you can see that these are data that I have appended to the to
the sets.
And after this, let's create our bar series in here.
And I can just take your bar series and let's print the sets.
And the boss's daughter open societies set zero and got up and set one and bar dot append and we have.
Said to.
Bar series dot upand we can set three and bar series dot a pan, and this is set for now author this
Let's create our line series.
So line series and cue line series.
And now we need to add some pine sauce, some data to the line series.
So let me just import queue point if.
So from Dodd Cuticura, we are going to quote you pint.
If so, we are going to add floating point in here.
Now let's create our chart.
So chart two, chart view, cue chart.
And now we can chart dot cities.
We want to add more series.
And also we need to add the line series.
And also, we can set title.
Wine and bar chart.
Let's create a chart view, CEW chart view, and we can add to the chart and the chart for you.
And then we can just say so dots at central widget to the chart.
Do the charts for you.
So now let's run this.
Now you can see that we have our line chart and also we have our bar chart.