In this lesson, we want to create a donut chart and peaked.
I'm going to create a new Python file and let me just call it donut dot pi.
And this is my code for creating of the window.
So donut chart.
And after this Now donut chart is a type of pie series.
So for that we need to import a pie series.
So from chart we are going to import Q chart, Q chart view and also Q pie series.
Now let's create our pie series.
So Q Pie series.
And after that we can add a hole size.
So dot, uh, set hole size and I can give the hole size in here and also we can append.
Uh, some text in here.
So for example, some data also, uh, protein 4.3% and I can add 4.3.
And also let's create our slice.
So my slice series dot append, and now we can add fat 15.6% and we can add the volume here.
After that, we can just say my slice dot set, explode it and make it a true.
Now we can append also, for example, I can just say other 30%
and dot append, uh, carbs.
57%.
And now let's create our chart.
Chart and we can add the series to the chart.
So add series like this, we can set animation dot set animation options.
Queue chart.
Dot animation options dot You can use all animation grid axis animation.
Let me just use series animations.
Set the title dot set.
Uh, title to do not chart.
Uh, also we can set theme.
So dot set.
Uh, and there are different theme that you can use.
So we can just use, uh.
Let me just use this brown sand.
And after this, we need to create the chart View.
Chart.
View.
Chart View.
And let's add the chart and the chart view.
And at the end we can just say self dot set central widget to the chart view.
And let's run our code.
And now you can see that we have a simple donut chart in here.