So we have already saw that how we can create our charts using pie.
Now how we can create our charts using QTC and also QML.
That's called markup language.
Now the first chart that we want to create, that's called line chart.
So let me create my QML file in here and let me just say line chart dot qml.
Now i already have a complete section on using QTC and also QML.
So before starting off this this section you can also check that section.
Now the first thing is that we are going to import our question here so we can just import qtquick 2.5
and also we are going to import QTC dot controls.
We can add the version and also we need to import charts.
So charts 2.5.
Now after this, let's create our application window in here.
And the first thing is that we need to create our window so I can just make it to true.
And also we can add a width of 600 and also a height of 400.
Now we can give a title to the window and that is line chart.
So.
And now we have created our dot HTML file and right now we can not run this.
We need to create another python file and we need to load our this dot HTML file.
Let me just create a another python file and let me just call it load.py.
So now let's create our let's add our imports.
So first from HTML, we are going to import QML application engine and also from core we are going to
import.
Q.
Object and from cutesy widgets, we want to import application.
Also, we are going to import sass.
Now let's create our window class that extends from object.
And let's create our init and also super.
And let me just remove this.
We do need that.
Okay.
Now, after this, let's create the object of our application or the instance of the application in
here.
We can pass this.org or if we're not using a command line utility, you can just leave it an empty list.
After that, we need to create the engine.
So in here I can just say engine QML application engine and after creating of the engine, now we can
create our window in here.
Also, we need to register our window and the context of the HTML so we can just say engine dot.
Root context.
Art.
Set context property and we can say window and we can add our window.
So after doing this now it's important point.
Now we need to load our QML file so we can use engine dot load and we can give the name of the queue.
So line chart dot qml.
And at the end we can just execute our app.
So app dot execute.
Now let's run this.
Run the load.
So we are not seeing anything.
It means that we have a.
Problem in here.
Application window.
Visible through width height.
So now the problem is in here.
I have a typo, so it's pretty quick.
Let's run it again.
Now you can see that we have our window in here.
Now let's create our charts.
So we have already imported our this cutie charts in here.
Now, so first, let me just comment this.
And now up first, I need to create my chart view in here.
And as I've already said, for creating our charts, first we need to create chart view and also we
need to create chart.
So in here we just we need to, we need chart view and here we do need to create chart.
We can just create, add our charts and the chart view.
So now I can just say anchors dot fill.
And I can just make it patent.
We can just say anti aliasing and we can just make it true.
Also, we can set the theme for this.
For example, chart view dot chart.
The team dark.
So now, after creating off the chart view, now we can add our line series in the chart view.
So I can just say line series.
You can add the name, for example name, and I can just say line series.
Now we can add our pints, so we can just say x, y pint and we can add the x pint.
So for example, zero and also Y to zero.
We can add another one.
So x, y, pint and.
X 1.1 and Y.
2.1.
Let's copy this.
And the X should be, for example, 1.9 and this should be 2.5.
For example, a 2.1 and it should be 3.11 or whatever.
You can just.
We want to add some data, some data points in here for the X and Y position.
3.4.
And four pint.
To.
And the last one is, for example, 4.3 and 3.1.
So now if I run this.
You can see that we are not seeing anything.
And that's because because we also need to add a cutie charts.
Now if I run this.
I am not seeing anything.
Let me first comment this and let's check that.
Where is the problem chart team talk and and here we have error like this and t it should be like this.
Let's run it again.
So we are not seeing any chart.
And that's because because we haven't imported the charts.
And again, we have problem.
And anti.
And this is the problem again, Ali.
It should be like this.
Yeah.
Now you can see that we have our line series in here.
And if I comment this, for example, and if I run this, you can see that we are not seeing any charts
because we need to import along with these we and also controls.
We need to import -- charts.
And if I run this, you can see that we have our line chart.