In this lesson, we want to create a bar chart or bar series using QTC and also QML.
So let's create a new python file in the file, not python file.
And I'm going to just say barchart dot qml and we can copy some codes from here.
Let me just copy these codes because I don't want to write these codes again.
And now let me just change this to Barchart.
And now we can create our bar series in the chart view.
So we can just say bar series.
We can add the ID.
So for example, my cities.
Now we can add our axis X and bar.
I got a goody axis0 and here we can add our categories and I can just say cata.
Goodies.
I can add some here.
So like this.
Now after adding these categories, let me just add one more.
Now we need to create our bar set so I can just say bar set and we need to give the label in here.
So for example, I can add some names and after that you need to give the values.
Two, two, three, four and five, six.
Okay.
And now let's just add.
Another one.
So, for example, John, and we can add some volume here, for example, 5 to 3, or we can just say
two, three.
And also let me change also this to five.
Change this to Bob and we can add some value in here.
Five eight Like this.
Okay.
So now let's just, uh, first we need to add this bar chart to the load engine dot load, bar chart,
dot HTML, and let's run this.
Uh.
Now you can see that we have our bar chart and if I run it again.
So this is our bar chart with the data that we have.