In this lesson, we want to learn that how we can create a stacked bar chart or a stacked bar series
using quick and QML.
Let's create another python file, not python but qml file.
And let me just call it stacked bar dot qml and we can just add or copy some codes.
So first we are going to just add these codes in here and let me change the title to uh, stacked.
Bar chart.
And let's close this.
Close this.
And now in here, we can create our stacked bar city.
So we can just say stacked bar cities like this.
We can add an ID.
So for example, my cities and let's add our some quotes from Barchart dot HTML and we can just grab
these quotes and add it in this section.
So we want to use the same data and there is no problem.
Let's add this to the load.py file.
So a stacked bokmal and we can run this.
So now we can see that we have a stacked bar chart in here.