In this lesson, we want to create pie series or pie chart using qtquick.
Now let's open our PyCharm and create our example.
I'm going to create a new XML file.
And let me just say pie chart dot HTML.
And as always, we can copy these codes from here.
Because I don't want to write these again.
And let's close this, close this and change this to pie chart.
And in here we can just say pie series.
Let's add ID to this.
So for example, Pie series and also we can add pie slice.
We should have the label.
So, for example, we can give Python and the value.
We can give a value for this.
Let's create another pie slice and the label is cplusplus and the value is 80.
Pie slice.
The label is Java and this is not comma, but it should be like this.
So Java and the value is 60 pie slice.
The label as.
C-sharp.
And the value is 40.
And now we can just add this to the engine dot load pie chart.
And let's run load.
Now you can see that we have our pi charm and qtc and also QML.