This is the last chart that we want to create and that will be scatter chart and quick.
Now let's create our example.
Let's create a dot HTML file in here and I'm going to just call it scatter dot HTML.
And let me just open this pie chart because we are going to copy some codes from here and paste it in
this section.
Okay, now let's create our scatter series in here.
Hope you can give ID so the ID is scattered one and the name is scatter one and let's add x, y pint.
So for the x, I want to give it 1.5.
And for the Y we can just say 1.5 and let's.
At some more points in here.
For example, I can change this to, uh.
Another volume and five, for example, five, five.
And I can just make it five seven and make it 1.8.
And like this, for example, one pine tree and also, uh, 2.5 and 2.1.
So let's just copy this.
And we want to add one more, uh, scatter series in here.
And let's change the ID to scatter, to scatter to.
And we can change the value to two point.
And 2.1.
2.5.
2.57.
And.
Uh, let's just make it like this, okay?
So now let's add this scatter dot QML and our this engine dot load scatter dot HTML.
Now if I run this so you can see that we have some points in here.
Scatter one.
So this is the scatter one and for the scatter two also we have some points in this section.